NIRAV BARIYA

Toronto, Ontario, nkb.bariya@gmail.com, +1(289)-968-9962, linkedin.com/in/nirav-bariya-a87984122/, github.com/b-n-i-r-a-v portfolio: b-nirav.github.io/portfolio/

SKILLS

SQL, Tableau, Python (NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, TensorFlow, Keras), Data Visualization, Data mining, Data Analytics, Machine Learning Models, Statistics, Project Management, Analytical Thinking Skills

PROJECTS

Instacart Customer Profile Analysis: *Python, Data Wrangling, Population Flows* April 2024 Conducted exploratory data analysis to uncover sales pattern, created new variables to develop customer profiles leading to better customer segmentation, presented actionable insights.

Influenza Staffing Plan: Tableau Dashboards, Excel, Story Telling

March 2024

Conducted in-depth analysis to provide staffing plan for Influenza season, integrated datasets, created research hypothesis, performed regression analysis, created spatial and temporal visualization to communicate the results and recommendations effectively.

Online Streaming Platform Launch: SQL, Tableau, Excel

April 2024

Executed extensive data analysis for a video rental company, resolved business questions by querying a relational database, and offered actionable insights to the sales and marketing team using Tableau visualizations.

Airbnb Toronto Analysis: Python, Scikit Learn, folium, K-Means Clustering

May 2024

Performed thorough analysis of Airbnb data to identify successful listings, performed regression to identify correlations, created clusters to determine factors behind the success and provided recommendations for the success through Tableau storyboard.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Anand Vidya Vihar School

June 2020-Sept 2023

High School Teacher of Mathematics

- Prepared lesson plans and maintained record of all the lesson plans to impart education of the highest quality leading to successful teaching learning processes.
- Monitored the implementation of the curriculum activities in all grades in line with the education board standards and maintained a detailed record of all activities and assessments.

Parul University June 2017-June 2018

Assistant Professor (Mathematics)

- Teaching undergraduate and graduate students from various departments through classroom lectures, conducting tutorial and problem-solving sessions, and taking practical in lab.
- Assess, review, and evaluate the progress and activities of the students using pen-paper examinations, lab practical tests, and viva-voce during the academic session

EDUCATION

Data Analytics Certificate	Jan 2024 - June 2024
CareerFoundry	
Google's Data Analytics Certificate	Oct 2023 – Dec 2023
Google, Coursera	
The Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda	June 2014 - April 2016
Master of Science in Mathematics	